David Gallo

dgallo.ca | david.gallo747@gmail.com | +33 06 23 40 06 55 | linkedin.com/in/davidgallo747 | github.com/monkeydg

SUMMARY

High-achieving trilingual technology consultant with five years of consulting and data science experience.

Completing an MSc in AI and Business Analytics at the Toulouse Business School. Graduated Summa Cum Laude from the University of Ottawa with an Honours Bachelor of Commerce.

HIGHLIGHTS

- Extensive machine learning experience
- Excellent communication skills
- Strong academic background
- Leadership outside of work and academics

EXPERIENCE

Deloitte Digital

May 2018 - Sep. 2018; Sep. 2019 - Dec. 2019; Jan. 2021 - Present

Consultant – Technology Consulting

- Led the QA team for a large-scale technology implementation with the federal government to overhaul a high-traffic citizen intake process. As QA Lead, I was directly responsible for the management of testing, automation, deployments, and project governance.
- Developed and implemented a benchmarking framework for a public utility company looking to overhaul its internal information and data management services and supporting technologies.
- Identified and analyzed business requirements for a cloud-based ERP implementation through workshops and independent research, then conducted a vendor market assessment.
- Created an IM framework and roadmap, then developed a target operating model for a complete service delivery overhaul of a federal public sector department.

Canadian Internet Registration Authority (CIRA)

May 2020 – Dec 2020

Cybersecurity Product Data Analyst

- Prototyped DNS firewall features in an agile environment using a scrum framework.
- Developed machine learning workflow using ElasticSearch (NoSQL database), MySQL, and Python to process DNS data in real-time and prepare it for data analysis.
- Implemented unsupervised machine learning techniques including hierarchical and density-based clustering to analyze millions of daily DNS requests and isolate malicious devices.
- Deployed the solution in a scalable Amazon AWS ecosystem.
- Created an API-driven dashboard to enable data-driven decision-making for marketing.

Department of National Defence

Jan. 2020 - May 2020

Accommodations Database Administrator

- Developed a comprehensive project plan to migrate business assets to MS SharePoint.
- Developed a SharePoint-hosted SQL database to manage all accommodations tracking.

Department of Fisheries and Oceans

May 2019 – Aug. 2019

Correspondence Officer, Legal Services

- Overhauled an integral SQL-based database to improve daily managerial operations.
- Managed time-critical requests for legal input by the Assistant Deputy Minister.

MNP LLP Jan. 2019 – May 2019

Analyst/Developer – Technology Consulting

- Performed in-depth research to compare leading DXP solutions and their application in various industries. Identified new client opportunities.
- Developed a comprehensive training curriculum for province-wide Tableau training
- Assessed current state IM practices of a public sector organization and defined the future state for a records management system, as well as a fit-gap analysis for native MS SharePoint capabilities.
- Acted as the sole content driver of two key proposals for business technology implementations.

Department of National Defence

Apr. 2017 – May 2018; Sep. 2018 – Dec. 2018

Records Management

- Managed the accessibility and security of vast amounts of data using OpenText solutions.
- Improved workplace efficiency by developing new methods to objectify client business requirements and scripted custom automation tools, leading to improved client interactions.

EDUCATION

Toulouse Business School

Aug. 2021 - Present

Master of Science in Artificial Intelligence and Business Analytics

Thesis: "Algorithmic Cryptocurrency Trading using Sentiment Analysis and Deep Q Neural Networks"

- 18.3/20 CGPA.
- First place presentation at the 2022 Datathon competition.

University of Ottawa

Sep. 2016 – Jun. 2021

Honours Bachelor of Commerce (Business Technology Management) (Co-op) (French Immersion) Summa Cum Laude

- 9.1.10 CGPA. Dean's Honour List.
- Selected for and completed the intensive two-year Profession of Management Consulting Program, to solve and present real business cases with leading consulting firms on a weekly basis.
- Selected for and completed the four-year International Certificate Program (Honours).

CERTIFICATIONS





Dell Data Science Associate

May 2022

Certification Number: 0T96TYPRG2E1143C

Microsoft Azure Data Scientist Associate

May 2022

Certification Number: I254-7240

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Fluent in English/French/Italian (DELF Level B2 and uOttawa French Immersion Certificate).
- Received awards including:
 - o JDC Coach of the Year (2022)
 - o Accenture Scholarship Fund (2020)
 - o University of Ottawa Merit Scholarship (2016-2020)
 - o JDC MIS 2nd Place (2019), JDC VIP Academic (2018-2019)
 - o Lazaridis International Case Conference 3rd Place (2018)
 - o AP Scholar Award (2016)
 - o Craig Cameron Memorial Scholarship (2016)
 - o Computer and IS Award (2015)
 - o Broadview Musicianship Award (2012)
 - o OPC Award for Student Leadership (2011)

LEADERSHIP

- Elected three times to the University of Ottawa Senate and Telfer Faculty Council (2018 to 2020), the highest academic governance bodies of the university and faculty. Provided input in all academic regulations, policies, and programs for the University.
- Musical Director for the CASCO Foundation to plan/perform a fundraising charity show raising money for the Children's Hospital of Eastern Ontario (CHEO).
- Director of Sponsorship of the Telfer Human Resources Association.
 - o Built and maintained relationships with association sponsors.
 - o Managed the leading source of revenue for the association.
- Vice President (Internal Affairs) of the Telfer Human Resources Association.
 - Oversaw all student affairs, including university relations and alumni networking.
 - Overhauled member recruitment strategies and implemented a new case management system.
- Sought a leading role in many other extra-curricular activities and case competitions, including:
 - o 2-time Academic VIP and 2019 Finalist at Jeux Du Commerce (the largest Eastern Canadian business case competition).
 - o Coach for the 2019-2023 JDC MIS teams.
 - o 3rd-place at the Lazaridis International Case Competition.

INTERESTS AND VOLUNTEERING

- Experienced with: Python, AWS, Azure, Elastic Stack, Apache Spark, SQL, NoSQL, Tableau, Keras/Tensorflow, Dynamics 365, SharePoint, OpenText Content Suite, Klipfolio, Jira, VBA.
- Volunteered regularly with the CASCO Foundation to support CHEO as a musician, helping raise \$250,000 CAD over three years, involving full-day weekly rehearsals.
- Founded the rock band AVRA; coordinated with industry professionals to perform at events including Ottawa's largest music festival (RBC Bluesfest), and to release music on the radio (Live 88.5).
- Completed Grade 8 Piano with the Royal Conservatory of Music after 14 years, practiced and performed drums for the last 10 years.